{
    "id": "47_Health_209",
    "claim": "There is no place in the world where you can escape the bite of a mosquito. I'm sorry. I'm sorry. or of the diseases that transmit. A chikungunya epidemic – whose virus is transmitted by a mosquito that stings in the day – is currently taking place in the Caribbean. In that region of America more than  cases are suspected in almost half of the islands, of which more than  have been confirmed. The infection also hit the mainland in French Guiana. Although we would like to exterminate them, disappearing mosquitoes from the face of the Earth could have disastrous effects on the ecosystem: their larvae process waste in the water where they are raised and adults have an important role in pollination. They are also a nutritious food source for creatures like mosquitofish, which swallows up to a hundred larvae a day. And even though malaria is perhaps the most known disease in the world, there are many other unpleasant conditions that spread thanks to these insects. Here we offer a list of five of those other diseases that a person can contract with just one bite. Yellow FeverThis is one of which football fans who attend the World Cup in Brazil have to watch. Every year, some  people around the world get yellow fever, most of them in sub-Saharan Africa. In , Cuban doctor and scientist Carlos Finlay was the first to suspect that the disease was transmitted by mosquitoes. But it was only  years later that his theory was confirmed. Control of the mosquito population helped the resumption of the Panama Canal, where until then one in ten men had died of yellow fever. Once the person gets infected, the fever appears a few days later. After apparent recovery, close to % of patients enter a second toxic phase that has a mortality rate of %. This is when the characteristic yellow coloration appears on the skin and on the white part of the eyes because it causes damage to the liver. This disease is also called black vomiting, a symptom of bleeding in the intestines. Fortunately, there is a vaccine that is recommended for anyone traveling to areas where yellow fever is endemic. DengueHalf of the world's population is in danger of getting dengue, which causes fever, severe headache, pain in the back of the eyes, joints and muscles, and rash in the skin. This is another tropical disease and is therefore present in Brazil. There is no specific vaccine or medicine to treat dengue. Support treatment includes rest, plenty of fluid and palliative medicines. Hemorrhagic dengue, an acute form of the disease, can be lethal. Unlike the Anopheles mosquito, which carries malaria and stings at night, Aedes aegypti is active during the day.'They start to sting soon after dawn, but towards the #NUMBER* it lowers the intensity because it is very hot. It resumes its activity at  or  until the sun goes down, and they are not active at night ', explains Dr. Philip McCall, dengue expert at Liverpool Tropical Medicine School, England. Dr. Ayan Panja contracted the most dangerous form of this disease during a vacation in Malaysia when he was in his  years. 'Honestly, after having these symptoms for a couple of days, I thought I was going to die. Good thing I was admitted to the Kuala Lumpur hospital where I had a platelet transfusion.\". Platelets are needed to help clot the blood. Dengue prevents the bone marrow from producing them, so bleeding is a serious complication of dengue. ChikungunyaIt may sound like some interesting place, but chikungunya is an unpleasant disease that causes high fever and pain in the joints.'It's debilitating. (People who suffer from it) cannot work and have to stay in bed with joint pain ', says Professor Johan Giusecke, chief scientist at the European Centre for Disease Control in Sweden. The first time Chikungunya was discussed was in an outbreak in Tanzania in . The name originates in a word in the Makonde language which means 'to become contortionist'. 'Most people experience a high fever for a short time, feel really sick and after about a week they pass ', explains Giusecke. 'But there have been cases of chikungunya in which joint pain lasts for weeks or in which, as a result of infection, the person becomes chronic arthritis ', he adds. 'Although not usually fatal, this disease can contribute to the death of fragile or older persons'. Last November we heard of the first case of chikungunya in America. It arose on the Caribbean island of San Martin. Far from its traditional place, in Africa, Southeast Asia and the Asian subcontinent, the infection has so far been responsible for four deaths. There is now a fear that the disease will spread to the United States, as the carrier mosquito also lives on the Texas coast and South Florida. According to the World Health Organization, since  there have been  millions of cases in India, Indonesia, Thailand, Maldives and Burma. Currently there is no cure or vaccine, so experts advise that the best way to deal with it is to avoid bites. The good news - if you can consider it as such - is that once the person becomes infected he becomes immune. La Crosse EncephalitisThis virus is named after the city of La Crosse, in Wisconsin, USA, where it was discovered in . Although it is quite rare - it only affects from  to  people a year in the US. USA. , most children-, those who contract this disease can have fever, headache, nausea, vomiting, fatigue and lethargy. More severe cases can cause attacks, coma, and paralysis. This virus moves between mosquitoes and small animals like squirrels, but humans cannot catch the latter. FilariasisThe first time it was described was  years ago, by Hindu and Persian doctors. Parasite worm Wuchereria bancrofti also spreads through mosquitoes. In acute cases it may cause elefantiasis. For larvae to develop in an adult worm it takes up to a year. Once they enter the human lymphatic system, the skin and underlying tissues thicken, especially in the legs, arms, breasts and genitals. It is a disease that disfigures and stigmatizes. The first time we talked about the transmission of this disease by a mosquito vector was in , by Patrick Manson. Early treatment can be very effective, but the drugs used have no effect on adult worms. How to defeat mosquitoes?For experts, the key to reducing the high number of mosquitoes vectors is to understand how insects behave. In addition to insecticides, other methods to control the number of mosquitoes can be odor traps, create genetically modified infertile mosquitoes and even use predatory crustaceans to eat larvae. Professor Hilary Ranson leads a fight against mosquitoes at Liverpool School of Tropical Medicine, and explains that one way to combat these insects is to exploit the fragile dynamics between mosquitoes, viruses and humans.'When the insect stings an infected person, the parasite needs a few *NOMBER* days to develop in your body. The mosquito only has a life of three weeks, so you need to take the pathogen early in your life so you can pass it by. So anything that reduces the daily survival rate will be effective.\". For its part, Philip McCall's goal is to determine the best way to eradicate mosquitoes with insecticides. Outdoor nebulization - going everywhere creating a fine insecticide mist - is a very visible method of control, but is often ineffective. The spraying behind closed doors, where the insecticide is sprayed inside the walls of the inhabitants to repell or kill mosquitoes, is much more effective, as it attacks them where they like to be. 'We are working with optical engineers to use sophisticated cameras to track each mosquito, to observe how they move in a three-dimensional space, where their favorite resting sites are ', adds McCall. So thinking like a mosquito could help scientists control them. I'm sorry.",
    "source": "www.bbc.com",
    "date": "02/04/2014",
    "veracity": 1,
    "claims": [
        {
            "claim": "it is no place in the world chikungunya can escape the bite it a mosquito.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What group of mosquitoes did bbc report was not able to escape the bite of a mosquito?",
                    "answer": "chikungunya"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How can chikungunya escape the bite of a mosquito?",
                    "score": 0.9169,
                    "answers": "can|aux\tchikungunya can escape the bite it a mosquito|relcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Is there any place in the world that chikungunya can escape the bite it a mosquito?",
                    "score": 0.9048,
                    "answers": "no|det"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the symptoms of chikungunya?",
                    "score": 0.805,
                    "answers": "the bite it a mosquito|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the spread of chikungunya?",
                    "score": 0.7896,
                    "answers": "the|det\tthe|det\ta|det\ta mosquito|appos"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the names of the mosquitoes that can catch chikungunya?",
                    "score": 0.7793,
                    "answers": "that|mark\tit|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "or of the diseases that transmit.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When did www.bbc.com report on diseases that transmit?",
                    "answer": "02/04/2014"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What diseases transmit?",
                    "score": 0.8888,
                    "answers": "on 02/04/2014|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many diseases transmit?",
                    "score": 0.8846,
                    "answers": "or|cc\tthe|det\tthat|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the names of the diseases that transmit?",
                    "score": 0.8421,
                    "answers": "that or of the diseases that transmit|dep\tthat transmit|relcl"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "A chikungunya epidemic – whose virus is transmitted yellow fever chikungunya mosquitoes and small animals like squirrels in the Caribbean.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What was the name of the epidemic that was reported on 02/04/2014 by www.bbc.com?",
                    "answer": "chikungunya epidemic"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the chikungunya epidemic?",
                    "score": 0.7775,
                    "answers": "that A chikungunya epidemic – whose virus is transmitted yellow fever chikungunya mosquitoes and small animals like squirrels in the Caribbean|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the chikungunya epidemic?",
                    "score": 0.7343,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\twww.bbc.com reported on 02/04/2014 that A chikungunya epidemic – whose virus is transmitted yellow fever chikungunya mosquitoes and small animals like squirrels in the Caribbean|ROOT\ton 02/04/2014|prep\tthat|mark\tA|det\t–|punct\twhose|poss\twhose virus|nsubjpass\tis|auxpass\twhose virus is transmitted|relcl\tyellow|amod\tyellow fever chikungunya mosquitoes and small animals like squirrels|appos\tand|cc\tsmall|amod\tsmall animals like squirrels|conj\tlike squirrels|prep\tsquirrels|pobj\tin the Caribbean|prep\tthe|det\tthe Caribbean|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is chikungunya?",
                    "score": 0.7141,
                    "answers": "chikungunya|compound\tchikungunya|compound\tchikungunya mosquitoes and small animals like squirrels|appos"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "In that mosquitoes and small animals like squirrels FilariasisThe the first case of chikungunya in America FilariasisThe the first case of chikungunya in America a second toxic phase that has a mortality rate of % Dr. Ayan Panja a second toxic phase that has a mortality rate of % than Parasite worm Wuchereria bancrofti .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported the first case of chikungunya in America?",
                    "answer": "Dr. Ayan Panja"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many cases of chikungunya were reported in America in 2014?",
                    "score": 0.7493,
                    "answers": "the first case of chikungunya in America|appos\tthe first case of chikungunya in America|appos"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the mortality rate of Chikungunya in America?",
                    "score": 0.7122,
                    "answers": "on 02/04/2014|prep\tthat|mark\tIn that|prep\tthat|pobj\tand|cc\tsmall|amod\tlike squirrels|prep\tsquirrels|pobj\tthe|det\tof chikungunya|prep\tchikungunya|pobj\tin America|prep\tFilariasisThe the first case of chikungunya in America a second toxic phase that has a mortality rate of %|appos\tthe|det\tof chikungunya|prep\tchikungunya|pobj\tin America|prep\ta|det\ttoxic|amod\tthat|nsubj\tthat has a mortality rate of %|relcl\ta|det\tmortality|compound\tof %|prep\tDr.|compound\tAyan|compound\ta|det\ttoxic|amod\tthat|nsubj\tthat has a mortality rate of %|relcl\ta|det\tmortality|compound\tof %|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is Dr. Ayan Panja's mortality rate?",
                    "score": 0.6635,
                    "answers": "Dr. Ayan Panja a second toxic phase that has a mortality rate of %|appos"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Parasite worm Wuchereria bancrofti the characteristic yellow coloration Dr. Ayan Panja the mainland in French Guiana.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the yellow coloration of Dr. Ayan Panja?",
                    "answer": "Parasite worm Wuchereria bancrofti"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is Parasite worm Wuchereria bancrofti?",
                    "score": 0.7303,
                    "answers": "Parasite|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What color is Dr. Ayan Panja?",
                    "score": 0.7165,
                    "answers": "characteristic|amod\tyellow|amod\tthe characteristic yellow coloration Dr. Ayan Panja|appos"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Where is Dr. Ayan Panja from?",
                    "score": 0.6681,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 02/04/2014 that Parasite worm Wuchereria bancrofti the characteristic yellow coloration Dr. Ayan Panja the mainland in French Guiana|ROOT\tthat Parasite worm Wuchereria bancrofti the characteristic yellow coloration Dr. Ayan Panja the mainland in French Guiana|npadvmod\tin French Guiana|prep\tFrench|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is Dr. Ayan Panja's color?",
                    "score": 0.6523,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\ton 02/04/2014|prep\tthat|mark\tWuchereria|compound\tWuchereria bancrofti|appos\tthe|det\tDr.|compound\tAyan|compound\tDr. Ayan Panja|appos\tthe|det"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Although we would chikungunya larvae disappearing them yellow fever face of the Platelets larvae chikungunya effects on America their larvae process waste in the water Platelets their larvae are raised and adults have an important role yellow fever .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What type of larvae disappeared from the Platelets?",
                    "answer": "chikungunya"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What do chikungunya larvae process?",
                    "answer": "waste in the water Platelets"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How do chikungunya larvae process waste in water platelets?",
                    "score": 0.7698,
                    "answers": "the water Platelets|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What does chikungunya larvae do with waste in the water platelets?",
                    "score": 0.6765,
                    "answers": "waste|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the effects of chikungunya on the larvae?",
                    "score": 0.6695,
                    "answers": "important|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the effect of chikungunya on children?",
                    "score": 0.6689,
                    "answers": "yellow fever face of the Platelets larvae chikungunya effects on America|dep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the symptoms of chikungunya?",
                    "score": 0.6661,
                    "answers": "on 02/04/2014|prep\tthat|mark\tAlthough|mark\twe|nsubj\tAlthough we would|aux\tchikungunya|compound\tchikungunya larvae|nsubj\tthem|dobj\tyellow|amod\tyellow fever|dep\tof the Platelets larvae|prep\tthe|det\tPlatelets|compound\tthe Platelets larvae|pobj\tchikungunya|compound\ton America|prep\ttheir|poss\ttheir larvae|nsubj\tthe|det\ttheir|poss\ttheir larvae|nsubjpass\tare|auxpass\tand|cc\tadults|nsubj\tan|det\tyellow|amod\tyellow fever|dobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "them are DengueHalf nutritious food source chikungunya like mosquitofish, which FilariasisThe to a hundred larvae a day.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What type of food source did bbc report that dengue is a good source of?",
                    "answer": "chikungunya"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What type of food source is chikungunya?",
                    "score": 0.7998,
                    "answers": "chikungunya|appos"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many larvae do mosquitofish have per day?",
                    "score": 0.7853,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 02/04/2014 that them are DengueHalf nutritious food source chikungunya like mosquitofish , which FilariasisThe to a hundred larvae a day|ROOT\tto a hundred larvae a day|prep\ta hundred larvae a day|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of the chikungunya?",
                    "score": 0.658,
                    "answers": "nutritious food source|appos"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is Filariasis?",
                    "score": 0.6362,
                    "answers": "that them are DengueHalf nutritious food source chikungunya like mosquitofish , which FilariasisThe to a hundred larvae a day|ccomp\tDengueHalf nutritious food source chikungunya like mosquitofish , which FilariasisThe to a hundred larvae a day|attr\tlike mosquitofish , which FilariasisThe to a hundred larvae a day|prep\tmosquitofish , which FilariasisThe to a hundred larvae a day|pobj\t,|punct\twhich|nsubj\twhich FilariasisThe to a hundred larvae a day|relcl\ta day|npadvmod"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "And even though malaria is perhaps the most known disease in the world DengueHalf there are many other unpleasant The good news Professor Johan Giusecke, chief scientist at the European Centre for Disease Control in Sweden .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on DengueHalf on 02/04/2014?",
                    "answer": "www.bbc.com"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Where does Professor Johan Giusecke work?",
                    "answer": "the European Centre for Disease Control in Sweden"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What disease is the most known in the world?",
                    "score": 0.824,
                    "answers": "European|compound\tfor Disease Control|prep\tDisease Control|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the European Centre for Disease Control in Sweden?",
                    "score": 0.6853,
                    "answers": "at the European Centre for Disease Control in Sweden|prep\tthe European Centre for Disease Control in Sweden|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Professor Johan Giusecke, chief scientist at the European Centre for Disease Control in Sweden the person Professor Johan Giusecke, chief scientist at the European Centre for Disease Control in Sweden La Crosse EncephalitisThis chikungunya just one bite.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "How many bites did the chikungunya have?",
                    "answer": "one"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Who is the chief scientist at the European Centre for Disease Control in Sweden La Crosse Encephalitis?",
                    "score": 0.7371,
                    "answers": "chief|amod\tchief|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of Professor Johan Giusecke's knowledge of the La Crosse Encephalitis?",
                    "score": 0.7316,
                    "answers": "Disease|compound\tDisease|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is La Crosse Encephalitis?",
                    "score": 0.7212,
                    "answers": "La|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between Professor Johan Giusecke and La Crosse Encephalitis?",
                    "score": 0.7053,
                    "answers": "in Sweden|prep\tin Sweden|prep\tjust one|nummod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is Encephalitis?",
                    "score": 0.7023,
                    "answers": "EncephalitisThis|appos"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Yellow FeverThis is one of which football fans who attend DengueHalf Cup in Brazil have to watch.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the name of the disease that football fans in the DengueHalf Cup in Brazil have to watch?",
                    "answer": "Yellow FeverThis is one of which football fans who attend DengueHalf Cup in Brazil have to watch"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many football fans attend the Dengue half cup in Brazil?",
                    "score": 0.8149,
                    "answers": "that|mark\tfootball fans who attend DengueHalf Cup in Brazil|nsubj\tin Brazil|prep\tto|aux"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of Yellow Fever?",
                    "score": 0.7452,
                    "answers": "Yellow FeverThis|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Every year, some  people around the world Most people get America yellow fever , most of some  people around the world in sub-Saharan Africa.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the name of the disease that some people around the world get every year?",
                    "answer": "yellow fever"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What are the symptoms of America's yellow fever?",
                    "score": 0.8631,
                    "answers": "yellow|compound\tyellow fever|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many people get America yellow fever every year?",
                    "score": 0.8502,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 02/04/2014 that Every year , some   people around the world Most people get America yellow fever , most of some   people around the world in sub - Saharan Africa|ROOT\tMost people get America yellow fever ,|acl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many people in sub-Saharan Africa get America yellow fever?",
                    "score": 0.8455,
                    "answers": "that|mark\tEvery|det\t,|punct\tpeople around the world|npadvmod\taround the world|prep\tthe world|pobj\tMost|amod\tMost people|nsubj\t,|punct\tof some|prep\tsome|pobj\taround the world|prep\tthe world|pobj\tsub|amod\t-|amod\tSaharan|amod\tsub - Saharan Africa|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many people die of America's yellow fever each year?",
                    "score": 0.8256,
                    "answers": "on 02/04/2014|prep\tEvery year , some  |dep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is America yellow fever?",
                    "score": 0.8188,
                    "answers": "the|det\tpeople around the world in sub - Saharan Africa|pobj\tthe|det"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "In , Cuban doctor and scientist Carlos Finlay mosquitoes Professor Johan Giusecke, chief scientist at the European Centre for Disease Control in Sweden to suspect that yellow fever was transmitted by mosquitoes.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When did Professor Johan Giusecke suspect yellow fever was transmitted by mosquitoes?",
                    "answer": "In"
                },
                {
                    "question": "When did Professor Johan Giusecke suspect yellow fever was transmitted by mosquitoes?",
                    "answer": "In"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What are the symptoms of Yellow Fever?",
                    "score": 0.7779,
                    "answers": "for Disease Control|prep\tDisease Control|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of Giusecke's knowledge of Yellow Fever?",
                    "score": 0.7495,
                    "answers": "Johan|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is Dr. Carlos Finlay's role in science?",
                    "score": 0.7318,
                    "answers": "scientist|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who is Carlos Finlay?",
                    "score": 0.73,
                    "answers": "Cuban doctor and scientist Carlos Finlay|nmod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who is professor Johan Giusecke?",
                    "score": 0.714,
                    "answers": "Professor Johan Giusecke , chief scientist at the European Centre for Disease Control in Sweden|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "But it was only mosquitoes that his theory was confirmed.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What was the only thing that confirmed bbc's theory?",
                    "answer": "mosquitoes"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the only thing that confirmed bbc's theory?",
                    "answer": "mosquitoes"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the only thing that confirmed bbc's theory?",
                    "answer": "mosquitoes"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many mosquitoes did Dr. George Flinn study?",
                    "score": 0.8943,
                    "answers": "only|advmod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many mosquitoes have been confirmed?",
                    "score": 0.8837,
                    "answers": "only mosquitoes that his theory was confirmed|attr"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many mosquitoes were confirmed in his theory?",
                    "score": 0.8596,
                    "answers": "that But it was only mosquitoes that his theory was confirmed|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of Johnson's theory on mosquitoes?",
                    "score": 0.8385,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 02/04/2014 that But it was only mosquitoes that his theory was confirmed|ROOT\tit|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Control of the mosquito population helped the resumption of the Panama Canal, where until then one in ten men had died of yellow fever.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "How many men died of yellow fever in the Panama Canal?",
                    "answer": "one in ten men"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What was the population of mosquitoes in the Panama Canal in 2014?",
                    "score": 0.8282,
                    "answers": "the mosquito population|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the effect of control of the mosquito population on the Panama Canal?",
                    "score": 0.8228,
                    "answers": "Control of the mosquito population|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Once the person gets infected, the fever appears a few days later.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When did www.bbc.com report that a person gets infected?",
                    "answer": "02/04/2014"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How long does it take for the flu to spread?",
                    "score": 0.8874,
                    "answers": "a few days|npadvmod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the symptoms of the flu?",
                    "score": 0.8617,
                    "answers": "on 02/04/2014|prep\tthe fever|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many days does it take to get infected?",
                    "score": 0.8562,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\tthat|mark\tOnce|mark\tthe|det\tthe person|nsubjpass\tgets|auxpass\tOnce the person gets infected|advcl\t,|punct\tthe|det\tthat Once the person gets infected , the fever appears a few days later|ccomp\ta|det\tfew|amod"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "After apparent recovery, close to % of patients enter a second toxic phase that has a mortality rate of %.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What percentage of patients enter a second toxic phase after apparent recovery?",
                    "answer": "close to %"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the mortality rate of patients who enter a second toxic phase?",
                    "score": 0.7575,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 02/04/2014 that After apparent recovery , close to % of patients enter a second toxic phase that has a mortality rate of %|ROOT\ton 02/04/2014|prep\tthat|mark\tapparent|amod\t,|punct\tclose|amod\tto|quantmod\tclose to % of patients|nsubj\tof patients|prep\tpatients|pobj\tthat After apparent recovery , close to % of patients enter a second toxic phase that has a mortality rate of %|ccomp\ta|det\ttoxic|amod\tthat|nsubj\tthat has a mortality rate of %|relcl\ta|det\tmortality|compound\ta mortality rate of %|dobj\tof %|prep\t%|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "This is when the characteristic yellow coloration appears on the skin and on the white part of the eyes because it causes damage to the liver.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "On what parts of the body does yellow color appear?",
                    "answer": "the skin and on the white part of the eyes"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What causes damage to the liver?",
                    "score": 0.7968,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 02/04/2014 that This is when the characteristic yellow coloration appears on the skin and on the white part of the eyes because it causes damage to the liver|ROOT\tthat|mark\tthat This is when the characteristic yellow coloration appears on the skin and on the white part of the eyes because it causes damage to the liver|ccomp\twhen|advmod\ton the skin and on the white part of the eyes|prep\tand|cc\ton the white part of the eyes|conj\twhite|amod\tthe white part of the eyes|pobj\tof the eyes|prep\tthe eyes|pobj\tbecause it causes damage to the liver|advcl\tto the liver|prep\tthe liver|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the symptoms of yellow coloration on skin and on the white part of eyes?",
                    "score": 0.7001,
                    "answers": "This|nsubj\tbecause|mark"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the characteristic coloration on the skin and white part of the eyes?",
                    "score": 0.6764,
                    "answers": "the characteristic yellow coloration|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "This disease is also called black vomiting, a symptom of bleeding in the intestines.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What is black vomiting?",
                    "answer": "a symptom of bleeding in the intestines"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is black vomiting?",
                    "score": 0.8043,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\twww.bbc.com reported on 02/04/2014 that This disease is also called black vomiting , a symptom of bleeding in the intestines|ROOT\ton 02/04/2014|prep\tthat|mark\tThis|det\tThis disease|nsubjpass\tis|auxpass\talso|advmod\tthat This disease is also called black vomiting , a symptom of bleeding in the intestines|ccomp\tblack|amod\tblack vomiting , a symptom of bleeding in the intestines|oprd\t,|punct\ta|det\ta symptom of bleeding in the intestines|appos\tof bleeding in the intestines|prep\tbleeding in the intestines|pobj\tin the intestines|prep\tthe|det\tthe intestines|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Fortunately, there is a vaccine that is recommended for anyone traveling to areas where yellow fever is endemic.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What is recommended for anyone traveling to areas where yellow fever is endemic?",
                    "answer": "a vaccine"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What vaccines are available for those who travel to areas where yellow fever is endemic?",
                    "score": 0.8815,
                    "answers": "a vaccine that is recommended for anyone traveling to areas where yellow fever is endemic|attr"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the symptoms of yellow fever?",
                    "score": 0.85,
                    "answers": "for anyone traveling to areas where yellow fever is endemic|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the best way to prevent the spread of yellow fever?",
                    "score": 0.817,
                    "answers": "that Fortunately , there is a vaccine that is recommended for anyone traveling to areas where yellow fever is endemic|ccomp\tthat is recommended for anyone traveling to areas where yellow fever is endemic|relcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the outbreak of yellow fever?",
                    "score": 0.8014,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 02/04/2014 that Fortunately , there is a vaccine that is recommended for anyone traveling to areas where yellow fever is endemic|ROOT\ton 02/04/2014|prep\tthat|mark\tFortunately|advmod\t,|punct\tthere|expl\ta|det\tthat|nsubjpass\tis|auxpass\tanyone traveling to areas where yellow fever is endemic|pobj\ttraveling to areas where yellow fever is endemic|acl\tto areas where yellow fever is endemic|prep\tareas where yellow fever is endemic|pobj\twhere|advmod\tyellow|amod\tyellow fever|nsubj\twhere yellow fever is endemic|relcl\tendemic|acomp"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "DengueHalf of the world's population is in danger of getting dengue, which causes fever, severe headache, pain in the back of the eyes, joints and muscles, and rash in the skin.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What does dengue cause?",
                    "answer": "dengue, which causes fever, severe headache, pain in the back of the eyes, joints and muscles, and rash in the skin"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What percentage of the world population are in danger of getting dengue?",
                    "score": 0.8597,
                    "answers": "that|mark\tthe|det\t,|punct\twhich|nsubj\t,|punct\t,|punct\tthe|det\tthe|det\t,|punct\tand|cc\t,|punct\tand|cc\tthe|det"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the symptoms of dengue?",
                    "score": 0.8145,
                    "answers": "in danger of getting dengue , which causes fever , severe headache , pain in the back of the eyes , joints and muscles , and rash in the skin|prep\tdanger of getting dengue , which causes fever , severe headache , pain in the back of the eyes , joints and muscles , and rash in the skin|pobj\tof getting dengue , which causes fever , severe headache , pain in the back of the eyes , joints and muscles , and rash in the skin|prep\tgetting dengue , which causes fever , severe headache , pain in the back of the eyes , joints and muscles , and rash in the skin|pcomp\tdengue , which causes fever , severe headache , pain in the back of the eyes , joints and muscles , and rash in the skin|dobj\twhich causes fever , severe headache , pain in the back of the eyes , joints and muscles , and rash in the skin|relcl\tfever , severe headache , pain in the back of the eyes , joints and muscles , and rash in the skin|dobj\tsevere|amod\tsevere headache , pain in the back of the eyes , joints and muscles , and rash in the skin|conj\tpain in the back of the eyes , joints and muscles , and rash in the skin|conj\tin the back of the eyes , joints and muscles|prep\tthe back of the eyes , joints and muscles|pobj\tof the eyes , joints and muscles|prep\tthe eyes , joints and muscles|pobj\tmuscles|conj\trash in the skin|conj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "This is another tropical disease and is therefore present in Brazil.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When did www.bbc.com report that this disease was present in Brazil?",
                    "answer": "02/04/2014"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What type of tropical disease is present in Brazil?",
                    "score": 0.9261,
                    "answers": "on 02/04/2014|prep\tthat This is another tropical disease and is therefore present in Brazil|ccomp\tis therefore present in Brazil|conj\tpresent in Brazil|acomp\tin Brazil|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many tropical diseases are there in Brazil?",
                    "score": 0.9171,
                    "answers": "another|det"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What type of disease is there in Brazil?",
                    "score": 0.9134,
                    "answers": "tropical|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the tropical disease in Brazil?",
                    "score": 0.8781,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\twww.bbc.com reported on 02/04/2014 that This is another tropical disease and is therefore present in Brazil|ROOT\tthat|mark\tThis|nsubj\tand|cc\ttherefore|advmod"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "There is no specific vaccine or medicine to treat dengue.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did www.bbc.com report on 02/04/2014",
                    "answer": "There is no specific vaccine or medicine to treat dengue"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Is there a specific vaccine to treat dengue?",
                    "score": 0.9498,
                    "answers": "on 02/04/2014|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What type of vaccines are available to treat dengue?",
                    "score": 0.9241,
                    "answers": "to treat dengue|relcl"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Support treatment includes rest, plenty of fluid and palliative medicines.",
            "question_answers": [],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of support for palliative medicine?",
                    "score": 0.8124,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 02/04/2014 that Support treatment includes rest , plenty of fluid and palliative medicines|ROOT\tSupport treatment|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is palliative medicine?",
                    "score": 0.7859,
                    "answers": "on 02/04/2014|prep\tthat Support treatment includes rest , plenty of fluid and palliative medicines|ccomp\trest , plenty of fluid and palliative medicines|dobj\tplenty of fluid and palliative medicines|conj\tof fluid and palliative medicines|prep\tfluid and palliative medicines|pobj\tpalliative|amod\tpalliative medicines|conj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Hemorrhagic dengue, an acute form of the disease, can be lethal.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When did bbc.com report that Hemorrhagic dengue can be lethal?",
                    "answer": "02/04/2014"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How lethal is Hemorrhagic dengue?",
                    "score": 0.9529,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\twww.bbc.com reported on 02/04/2014 that Hemorrhagic dengue , an acute form of the disease , can be lethal|ROOT\ton 02/04/2014|prep\tthe disease|pobj\tcan|aux\tthat Hemorrhagic dengue , an acute form of the disease , can be lethal|ccomp\tlethal|acomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is Hemorrhagic dengue?",
                    "score": 0.8856,
                    "answers": "that|mark\tHemorrhagic|amod\tHemorrhagic dengue , an acute form of the disease ,|nsubj\t,|punct\tan|det\tacute|amod\tan acute form of the disease|appos\tof the disease|prep\tthe|det\t,|punct"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Unlike the Anopheles mosquito, which carries malaria and stings at night, Aedes aegypti is active during the day.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What mosquito is active during the day?",
                    "answer": "Aedes aegypti"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is Aedes aegypti active during the day?",
                    "score": 0.7528,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 02/04/2014 that Unlike the Anopheles mosquito , which carries malaria and stings at night , Aedes aegypti is active during the day|ROOT\ton 02/04/2014|prep\tthat|mark\tthe|det\t,|punct\twhich|nsubj\tmalaria|dobj\tand|cc\tstings at night|conj\tat night|prep\tnight|pobj\t,|punct\tthat Unlike the Anopheles mosquito , which carries malaria and stings at night , Aedes aegypti is active during the day|ccomp\tactive|acomp\tduring the day|prep\tthe|det\tthe day|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the symptoms of Aedes aegypti?",
                    "score": 0.7381,
                    "answers": "Unlike the Anopheles mosquito , which carries malaria and stings at night|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is Aedes aegypti?",
                    "score": 0.7007,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\tAnopheles|compound\tthe Anopheles mosquito , which carries malaria and stings at night|pobj\twhich carries malaria and stings at night|relcl\tAedes|compound\tAedes aegypti|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "'They start to sting soon after dawn, but towards the #NUMBER* it lowers the intensity because it is very hot.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 02/04/2014 that 'They start to sting soon after dawn, but towards the #NUMBER* it lowers the intensity?",
                    "answer": "www.bbc.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the method used to measure the sting rate of insects?",
                    "score": 0.7318,
                    "answers": "on 02/04/2014|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What does it mean to sting soon after dawn?",
                    "score": 0.7236,
                    "answers": "to sting soon after dawn|xcomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between the numberNUMBER and the intensity of sting?",
                    "score": 0.6343,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 02/04/2014 that ' They start to sting soon after dawn , but towards the # NUMBER * it lowers the intensity because it is very hot|ROOT"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What does the #NUMBER number mean?",
                    "score": 0.6123,
                    "answers": "that ' They start to sting soon after dawn , but towards the # NUMBER * it lowers the intensity because it is very hot|ccomp\ttowards the # NUMBER *|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What does the acronym \"NUMBER\" mean?",
                    "score": 0.5866,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\tvery hot|acomp"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "It resumes its activity at  or  until the sun goes down, and they are not active at night ', explains Dr. Philip McCall, dengue expert at Liverpool Tropical Medicine School, England.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did bbc.com say about them at night?",
                    "answer": "they are not active at night"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the active activity of dengue?",
                    "score": 0.7864,
                    "answers": "active|acomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the activity of dengue?",
                    "score": 0.7738,
                    "answers": "that It resumes its activity at|ccomp\tits activity|dobj\tdengue|compound\tTropical|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the symptoms of dengue?",
                    "score": 0.7484,
                    "answers": "  until the sun goes down , and they are not active at night|dep\tuntil the sun goes down , and they are not active at night|advcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is Dr. Philip McCall's position on dengue?",
                    "score": 0.7345,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\ton 02/04/2014|prep\tthat|mark\tIt|nsubj\tits|poss\tat|prep\t  or|dep\tor|cc\tuntil|mark\tthe|det\tdown|prt\t,|punct\tand|cc\tthey|nsubj\tnot|neg\t'|punct\t,|punct\twww.bbc.com reported on 02/04/2014 that It resumes its activity at   or   until the sun goes down , and they are not active at night ' , explains Dr. Philip McCall , dengue expert at Liverpool Tropical Medicine School , England|ROOT\tDr.|compound\tPhilip|compound\tDr. Philip McCall , dengue expert at Liverpool Tropical Medicine School , England|nsubj\t,|punct\tdengue expert at Liverpool Tropical Medicine School , England|appos\tLiverpool|compound\tTropical Medicine|compound\t,|punct"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Dr. Ayan Panja contracted the most dangerous form of this disease during a vacation in Malaysia when he was in his  years.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who contracted the most dangerous form of Alzheimer's disease during a vacation in Malaysia?",
                    "answer": "Dr. Ayan Panja"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "When did Dr. Ayan Panja contracted the most dangerous form of this disease during a vacation in Malaysia?",
                    "score": 0.8375,
                    "answers": "when he was in his|advcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How dangerous is Dr. Ayan Panja?",
                    "score": 0.8196,
                    "answers": "most dangerous|amod\tthe most dangerous form of this disease|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is Dr. Ayan Panja's role in the disease?",
                    "score": 0.7207,
                    "answers": "in his|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "'Honestly, after having these symptoms for a couple of days, I thought I was going to die.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When did www.bbc.com report that 'Honestly, after having these symptoms for a couple of days, I thought I was going to die'?",
                    "answer": "02/04/2014"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How long did the symptoms last?",
                    "score": 0.8541,
                    "answers": "after having these symptoms for a couple of days|prep\tfor a couple of days|prep\tof days|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the symptoms of the flu?",
                    "score": 0.8181,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many days after the symptoms were there?",
                    "score": 0.796,
                    "answers": "days|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the cause of the symptoms after the symptoms for a couple of days?",
                    "score": 0.7268,
                    "answers": "that ' Honestly , after having these symptoms for a couple of days , I thought I was going to die|ccomp"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Good thing I was admitted to the Kuala Lumpur hospital where I had a platelet transfusion.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Where was my platelet transfusion performed?",
                    "answer": "Kuala Lumpur"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many people were admitted to the Kuala Lumpur hospital for a platelet transfusion in 2014?",
                    "score": 0.8183,
                    "answers": "Good|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many platelet transfusions were performed in Malaysia in 2014?",
                    "score": 0.7998,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 02/04/2014 that Good thing I was admitted to the Kuala Lumpur hospital where I had a platelet transfusion|ROOT\tI was admitted to the Kuala Lumpur hospital where I had a platelet transfusion|acl\tplatelet|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the blood transfusion?",
                    "score": 0.7121,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Platelets are needed to help clot the blood.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What is needed to help clot the blood?",
                    "answer": "Platelets"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How much blood is needed to clot?",
                    "score": 0.9061,
                    "answers": "that Platelets are needed to help clot the blood|ccomp\tclot the blood|xcomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many platelets are needed to clot the blood?",
                    "score": 0.8951,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 02/04/2014 that Platelets are needed to help clot the blood|ROOT\ton 02/04/2014|prep\tthat|mark\tare|auxpass\tto|aux\tthe|det\tthe blood|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the purpose of clotting blood?",
                    "score": 0.8369,
                    "answers": "to help clot the blood|advcl"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Dengue prevents the bone marrow from producing them, so bleeding is a serious complication of dengue.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What is a serious complication of dengue?",
                    "answer": "bleeding"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What are the symptoms of dengue?",
                    "score": 0.8396,
                    "answers": "on 02/04/2014|prep\tthe|det\tthem|dobj\t,|punct\tso|advmod\tbleeding|nsubj\ta|det\tserious|amod\ta serious complication of dengue|attr\tof dengue|prep\tdengue|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the process used to produce dengue?",
                    "score": 0.8216,
                    "answers": "from producing them|prep\tproducing them|pcomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of Dengue's effect on bone marrow production?",
                    "score": 0.7975,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 02/04/2014 that Dengue prevents the bone marrow from producing them , so bleeding is a serious complication of dengue|ROOT"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "ChikungunyaIt may sound like some interesting place, but chikungunya is an unpleasant disease that causes high fever and pain in the joints.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What does chikungunya cause?",
                    "answer": "high fever and pain in the joints"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What are the symptoms of Chikungunya?",
                    "score": 0.7823,
                    "answers": "the joints|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is Chikungunya?",
                    "score": 0.7461,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\twww.bbc.com reported on 02/04/2014 that ChikungunyaIt may sound like some interesting place , but chikungunya is an unpleasant disease that causes high fever and pain in the joints|ROOT\ton 02/04/2014|prep\t02/04/2014|pobj\tthat|mark\tChikungunyaIt|nsubj\tmay|aux\tthat ChikungunyaIt may sound like some interesting place|ccomp\tlike some interesting place|prep\tsome|det\tinteresting|amod\tsome interesting place|pobj\t,|punct\tbut|cc\tan|det\tunpleasant|amod\tan unpleasant disease that causes high fever and pain in the joints|attr\tthat|nsubj\tthat causes high fever and pain in the joints|relcl\thigh|amod\tand|cc\tpain in the joints|conj\tin the joints|prep\tthe|det"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is chikungunya?",
                    "score": 0.7461,
                    "answers": "chikungunya|nsubj\tchikungunya is an unpleasant disease that causes high fever and pain in the joints|conj\thigh fever and pain in the joints|dobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "(People who suffer from it) cannot work and have to stay in bed with joint pain ', says Professor Johan Giusecke, chief scientist at the European Centre for Disease Control in Sweden.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What do people who suffer from arthritis have to stay in bed with?",
                    "answer": "joint pain"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many people suffer from joint pain?",
                    "score": 0.842,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\twww.bbc.com reported on 02/04/2014 that ( People who suffer from it ) can not work and have to stay in bed with joint pain|ccomp\ton 02/04/2014|prep\tthat|mark\t(|punct\tPeople who suffer from it|nsubj\twho|nsubj\twho suffer from it|relcl\tfrom it|prep\tit|pobj\t)|punct\tcan|aux\tnot|neg\tthat ( People who suffer from it ) can not work and have to stay in bed with joint pain|ccomp\tand|cc\thave to stay in bed with joint pain|conj\tto|aux\tto stay in bed with joint pain|xcomp\tin bed|prep\tbed|pobj\twith joint pain|prep\tjoint|compound\tjoint pain|pobj\t'|punct\t,|punct\twww.bbc.com reported on 02/04/2014 that ( People who suffer from it ) can not work and have to stay in bed with joint pain ' , says Professor Johan Giusecke , chief scientist at the European Centre for Disease Control in Sweden|ROOT\tJohan|compound\t,|punct\tat the European Centre for Disease Control in Sweden|prep\tthe|det\tEuropean|compound\tthe European Centre for Disease Control in Sweden|pobj\tfor Disease Control|prep\tDisease|compound\tDisease Control|pobj\tin Sweden|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is Dr. Johan Giusecke's position on joint pain?",
                    "score": 0.7585,
                    "answers": "Professor|compound\tchief|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who is Professor Johan Giusecke?",
                    "score": 0.668,
                    "answers": "Professor Johan Giusecke , chief scientist at the European Centre for Disease Control in Sweden|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The first time Chikungunya was discussed was in an outbreak in Tanzania in .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Where was the first time Chikungunya was discussed?",
                    "answer": "Tanzania"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "When did the Chikungunya outbreak occur in Tanzania?",
                    "score": 0.9514,
                    "answers": "on 02/04/2014|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the outbreak of Chikungunya in Tanzania?",
                    "score": 0.9211,
                    "answers": "in Tanzania|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the Chikungunya outbreak in Tanzania in 2014?",
                    "score": 0.9197,
                    "answers": "in an outbreak in Tanzania in|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "When was the last time Chikungunya was discussed in Tanzania?",
                    "score": 0.9177,
                    "answers": "that The first time Chikungunya was discussed was in an outbreak in Tanzania in|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the Chikungunya outbreak?",
                    "score": 0.8657,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The name originates in a word in the Makonde language which means 'to become contortionist'.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "In what language is the name 'The name of a contortionist' derived from?",
                    "answer": "Makonde"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the origin of the word contortionist?",
                    "score": 0.7659,
                    "answers": "contortionist|attr"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "'Most people experience a high fever for a short time, feel really sick and after about a week they pass ', explains Giusecke.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What happens to most people after a week of feeling sick?",
                    "answer": "after about a week they pass"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many people experience high fever for a short time?",
                    "score": 0.7719,
                    "answers": "on 02/04/2014|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of Giusecke's statistics?",
                    "score": 0.6346,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "'But there have been cases of chikungunya in which joint pain lasts for weeks or in which, as a result of infection, the person becomes chronic arthritis ', he adds.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What does chikungunya cause?",
                    "answer": "chronic arthritis"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What does chikungunya cause?",
                    "answer": "chronic arthritis"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What are the symptoms of chikungunya?",
                    "score": 0.8307,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\twww.bbc.com reported on 02/04/2014|ccomp\ton 02/04/2014|prep\tthat|mark\t'|punct\tBut|cc\tthere|expl\thave|aux\tBut there have been cases of chikungunya in which joint pain lasts for weeks or in which , as a result of infection , the person becomes chronic arthritis|ccomp\tcases of chikungunya in which joint pain lasts for weeks or in which , as a result of infection , the person becomes chronic arthritis|attr\tof chikungunya in which joint pain lasts for weeks or in which , as a result of infection , the person becomes chronic arthritis|prep\tchikungunya in which joint pain lasts for weeks or in which , as a result of infection , the person becomes chronic arthritis|pobj\tin which|prep\twhich|pobj\tjoint|compound\tjoint pain|nsubj\tin which joint pain lasts for weeks or in which , as a result of infection , the person becomes chronic arthritis|relcl\tfor weeks|prep\tor|cc\tin which|prep\twhich|pobj\t,|punct\tas a result of infection|prep\ta|det\ta result of infection|pobj\tof infection|prep\tinfection|pobj\t,|punct\tthe|det\tthe person|nsubj\tin which , as a result of infection , the person becomes chronic arthritis|conj\tchronic|amod\t'|punct\t,|punct\the|nsubj\twww.bbc.com reported on 02/04/2014 that ' But there have been cases of chikungunya in which joint pain lasts for weeks or in which , as a result of infection , the person becomes chronic arthritis ' , he adds|ROOT"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "'Although not usually fatal, this disease can contribute to the death of fragile or older persons'.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 'Although not usually fatal, this disease can contribute to the death of fragile or older persons'?",
                    "answer": "www.bbc.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the mortality rate of those with the disease?",
                    "score": 0.8887,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\ton 02/04/2014|prep\tthis disease|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the death rate of fragile or older persons?",
                    "score": 0.8687,
                    "answers": "that|mark\t'|punct\tAlthough|mark\tnot|neg\tusually|advmod\tAlthough not usually fatal|advcl\t,|punct\tthis|det\tcan|aux\tthe|det\tfragile or older|amod\tor|cc\t'|punct"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Last November we heard of the first case of chikungunya in America.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When did bbc.com report on the first case of chikungunya in America?",
                    "answer": "02/04/2014"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "When was the first case of chikungunya reported in America?",
                    "score": 0.9173,
                    "answers": "Last|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is chikungunya?",
                    "score": 0.7884,
                    "answers": "of chikungunya|prep\tchikungunya|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "It arose on the Caribbean island of San Martin.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When did www.bbc.com report that it arose on the Caribbean island of San Martin?",
                    "answer": "02/04/2014"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Where is the Caribbean island of San Martin located?",
                    "score": 0.8926,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\ton the Caribbean island of San Martin|prep\tthe Caribbean island of San Martin|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the location of the island of San Martin?",
                    "score": 0.7952,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 02/04/2014 that It arose on the Caribbean island of San Martin|ROOT\ton 02/04/2014|prep\tthat|mark\tIt|nsubj\tthe|det"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Far from its traditional place, in Africa, Southeast Asia and the Asian subcontinent, the infection has so far been responsible for four deaths.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "How many deaths have been caused by the TB infection in Africa, Southeast Asia, and the Asian subcontinent?",
                    "answer": "four"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many deaths have been caused by the HIV outbreak in Africa?",
                    "score": 0.8776,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 02/04/2014 that Far from its traditional place , in Africa , Southeast Asia and the Asian subcontinent , the infection has so far been responsible for four deaths|ROOT"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many deaths occurred from HIV in Africa in 2014?",
                    "score": 0.8666,
                    "answers": "its|poss"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "There is now a fear that the disease will spread to the United States, as the carrier mosquito also lives on the Texas coast and South Florida.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Where does the carrier mosquito live?",
                    "answer": "the carrier mosquito also lives on the Texas coast and South Florida"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Where is the carrier mosquito located on the Texas coast?",
                    "score": 0.8574,
                    "answers": "on the Texas coast and South Florida|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the spread of the carrier mosquito?",
                    "score": 0.8483,
                    "answers": "that the disease will spread to the United States , as the carrier mosquito also lives on the Texas coast and South Florida|acl"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "According to the World Health Organization, since  there have been  millions of cases in India, Indonesia, Thailand, Maldives and Burma.",
            "question_answers": [],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "According to the World Health Organization, how many cases have been reported in India, Indonesia, Thailand, Maldives, and Burma?",
                    "score": 0.8191,
                    "answers": " |dep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Currently there is no cure or vaccine, so experts advise that the best way to deal with it is to avoid bites.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When did www.bbc.com report that there is no cure or vaccine?",
                    "answer": "02/04/2014"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the best way to deal with mosquito bites?",
                    "score": 0.7909,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\twww.bbc.com reported on 02/04/2014 that Currently there is no cure or vaccine , so experts advise that the best way to deal with it is to avoid bites|ROOT\ton 02/04/2014|prep\tthat|mark\tCurrently|advmod\tthere|expl\tthat Currently there is no cure or vaccine|ccomp\tno|det\tno cure or vaccine|attr\tor|cc\tvaccine|conj\t,|punct\tso|dep\texperts|nsubj\t, so experts advise that the best way to deal with it is to avoid bites|advcl\tthat|mark\tthe|det\tbest|amod\tthe best way to deal with it|nsubj\tto|aux\tto deal with it|relcl\twith it|prep\tit|pobj\tthat the best way to deal with it is to avoid bites|ccomp\tto|aux\tto avoid bites|xcomp\tbites|dobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The good news - if you can consider it as such - is that once the person becomes infected he becomes immune.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the good news?",
                    "answer": "once the person becomes infected he becomes immune"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What does it mean to become immune?",
                    "score": 0.8739,
                    "answers": "good|amod\tit|dobj\tthat The good news - if you can consider it as such - is that once the person becomes infected he becomes immune|ccomp\timmune|acomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many people become immune if they become infected?",
                    "score": 0.8462,
                    "answers": "on 02/04/2014|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What happens to the person who becomes infected if they become immune?",
                    "score": 0.8453,
                    "answers": "once the person becomes infected|advcl\tthat once the person becomes infected he becomes immune|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the average immunization rate for a person who becomes infected?",
                    "score": 0.845,
                    "answers": "as such|prep\tthe person|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the best way to determine if an infected person is immune?",
                    "score": 0.817,
                    "answers": "The|det\tThe good news|nsubj\t-|punct\tif|mark\tif you can consider it as such|advcl\tsuch|amod\t-|punct"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "La Crosse EncephalitisThis virus is named after the city of La Crosse, in Wisconsin, USA, where it was discovered in .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "On what date was the La Crosse Encephalitis virus discovered?",
                    "answer": "02/04/2014"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Where was La Crosse Encephalitis found?",
                    "score": 0.9133,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 02/04/2014 that La Crosse EncephalitisThis virus is named after the city of La Crosse , in Wisconsin , USA , where it was discovered in|ROOT\tafter the city of La Crosse , in Wisconsin , USA , where it was discovered in|prep\tWisconsin , USA|pobj\twhere|advmod\twhere it was discovered in|relcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Where is La Crosse Encephalitis located?",
                    "score": 0.8595,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is La Crosse Encephalitis?",
                    "score": 0.823,
                    "answers": "on 02/04/2014|prep\tthat|mark\tLa|compound\tthat La Crosse EncephalitisThis|nmod\tthat La Crosse EncephalitisThis virus|nsubjpass\tis|auxpass\tthat La Crosse EncephalitisThis virus is named after the city of La Crosse , in Wisconsin , USA , where it was discovered in|punct\tthe|det\tthe city of La Crosse , in Wisconsin , USA , where it was discovered in|pobj\tof La Crosse|prep\tLa|compound\t,|punct\tin Wisconsin , USA|prep\t,|punct\t,|punct\tit|nsubjpass\twas|auxpass\tin|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Although it is quite rare - it only affects from  to  people a year in the US.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "On what date did www.bbc.com report that the flu affects people only a few times a year in the US?",
                    "answer": "02/04/2014"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How long does it last in the US?",
                    "answer": "a year"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many people are affected by the flu each year in the United States?",
                    "score": 0.7648,
                    "answers": "on 02/04/2014|prep\tthat|mark\tAlthough|mark\tit|nsubj\tAlthough it is quite rare|advcl\tquite|advmod\tquite rare|acomp\t-|punct\tit|nsubj\tfrom|prep\t  to|dep\tpeople a year in the US|dobj\ta|det\tin the US|prep\tthe|det\tthe US|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "USA.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "On what date did www.bbc.com report that the USA was in the US?",
                    "answer": "02/04/2014"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What does thebbc.com website do?",
                    "score": 0.8078,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between the USA and the USA?",
                    "score": 0.6022,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 02/04/2014 that USA|ROOT"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the relationship between USA and USA?",
                    "score": 0.5723,
                    "answers": "on 02/04/2014|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": ", most children-, those who contract this disease can have fever, headache, nausea, vomiting, fatigue and lethargy.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When did www.bbc.com report that most children who contract Alzheimer's disease can have fever, headache, nausea, vomiting, fatigue, and lethargy?",
                    "answer": "02/04/2014"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What are the symptoms of the flu?",
                    "score": 0.8647,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 02/04/2014 that , most children- , those who contract this disease can have fever , headache , nausea , vomiting , fatigue and lethargy|ROOT\tthat , most children- , those who contract this disease can have fever , headache , nausea , vomiting , fatigue and lethargy|ccomp\tfever , headache , nausea , vomiting , fatigue and lethargy|dobj\theadache , nausea , vomiting , fatigue and lethargy|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many children who contract the disease have fever, headache, nausea, vomiting, and lethargy?",
                    "score": 0.8441,
                    "answers": "most|amod"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "More severe cases can cause attacks, coma, and paralysis.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What type of cases can cause attacks, coma, and paralysis?",
                    "answer": "More severe cases"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How severe are attacks, coma, and paralysis?",
                    "score": 0.898,
                    "answers": "More severe|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the symptoms of severe cases of brain damage?",
                    "score": 0.8458,
                    "answers": "on 02/04/2014|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "This virus moves between mosquitoes and small animals like squirrels, but humans cannot catch the latter.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who can't catch the virus?",
                    "answer": "humans"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How do humans catch the virus between mosquitoes and small animals?",
                    "score": 0.921,
                    "answers": "that This virus moves between mosquitoes and small animals like squirrels , but humans can not catch the latter|ccomp"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "FilariasisThe first time it was described was  years ago, by Hindu and Persian doctors.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who first described Filariasis?",
                    "answer": "Hindu and Persian"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is Filariasis?",
                    "score": 0.7871,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\twww.bbc.com reported on 02/04/2014 that FilariasisThe first time it was described was|ROOT\ton 02/04/2014|prep\tthat|mark\tFilariasisThe|dep\tfirst time it was described|nsubj\tit|nsubjpass\twas|auxpass\tit was described|relcl\tthat FilariasisThe first time it was described was|ccomp\t  years ago , by Hindu and Persian doctors|dep\tyears|npadvmod\tyears ago ,|advmod\t,|punct\tyears ago , by Hindu and Persian doctors|agent\tHindu and Persian|amod\tand|cc\tHindu and Persian doctors|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Parasite worm Wuchereria bancrofti also spreads through mosquitoes.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What worm spreads through mosquitoes?",
                    "answer": "Parasite worm Wuchereria bancrofti"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How can parasites spread through mosquitoes?",
                    "score": 0.9206,
                    "answers": "mosquitoes|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the spread of Parasite worm Wuchereria bancrofti?",
                    "score": 0.8543,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\twww.bbc.com reported on 02/04/2014 that Parasite worm Wuchereria bancrofti also spreads through mosquitoes|ROOT\tthrough mosquitoes|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is Wuchereria bancrofti?",
                    "score": 0.7965,
                    "answers": "Wuchereria|compound"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "In acute cases it may cause elefantiasis.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did bbc.com report that in acute cases it may cause?",
                    "answer": "elefantiasis"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What are the symptoms of elefantiasis?",
                    "score": 0.8657,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\ton 02/04/2014|prep\tIn acute cases|prep\tacute|amod\tacute cases|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is elefantiasis?",
                    "score": 0.8265,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 02/04/2014 that In acute cases it may cause elefantiasis|ROOT\tthat|mark\tit|nsubj\tmay|aux\tthat In acute cases it may cause elefantiasis|ccomp\telefantiasis|dobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "For larvae to develop in an adult worm it takes up to a year.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "How long does it take for larvae to develop in an adult worm?",
                    "answer": "up to a year"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How long does it take to develop an adult worm?",
                    "score": 0.9004,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\twww.bbc.com reported on 02/04/2014 that For larvae to develop in an adult worm it takes up to a year|ROOT\ton 02/04/2014|prep\tthat|mark\tFor|mark\tlarvae|nsubj\tto|aux\tFor larvae to develop in an adult worm|advcl\tin an adult worm|prep\tan|det\tadult|compound\tan adult worm|pobj\tit|nsubj\tthat For larvae to develop in an adult worm it takes up to a year|ccomp\tup|quantmod\tto|quantmod\tup to a|nummod"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Once they enter the human lymphatic system, the skin and underlying tissues thicken, especially in the legs, arms, breasts and genitals.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What happens to the skin and underlying tissues once they enter the human lymphatic system?",
                    "answer": "the skin and underlying tissues thicken, especially in the legs, arms, breasts and genitals"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What happens to the organs after they enter the human lymphatic system?",
                    "score": 0.7379,
                    "answers": "Once they enter the human lymphatic system|advcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the effects of human lymphatic system on organs?",
                    "score": 0.7103,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\ton 02/04/2014|prep\tthe skin and underlying tissues|nsubj\tespecially|advmod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between the body and the organs when they enter human lymphatic system?",
                    "score": 0.6685,
                    "answers": "arms , breasts and genitals|conj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "It is a disease that disfigures and stigmatizes.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on the disease?",
                    "answer": "www.bbc.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What disease disfigures and stigmatizes?",
                    "score": 0.9069,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\twww.bbc.com reported on 02/04/2014 that It is a disease that disfigures and stigmatizes|ROOT\ton 02/04/2014|prep\tthat|mark\tIt|nsubj\ta|det\tthat|nsubj\tand|cc\tstigmatizes|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the disease that disfigures and stigmatizes?",
                    "score": 0.817,
                    "answers": "that It is a disease that disfigures and stigmatizes|ccomp\ta disease that disfigures and stigmatizes|attr\tthat disfigures and stigmatizes|relcl"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The first time we talked about the transmission of this disease by a mosquito vector was in , by Patrick Manson.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When was the first time we talked about the transmission of the disease by a mosquito vector?",
                    "answer": "in"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did Patrick Manson say about the transmission of the disease by a mosquito?",
                    "score": 0.8102,
                    "answers": "The first time we talked about the transmission of this disease by a mosquito vector|nsubj\twe talked about the transmission of this disease by a mosquito vector|relcl\tabout the transmission of this disease by a mosquito vector|prep\tthe transmission of this disease by a mosquito vector|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of Patrick Manson's virus?",
                    "score": 0.6754,
                    "answers": "by a mosquito vector|prep\ta mosquito vector|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Early treatment can be very effective, but the drugs used have no effect on adult worms.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What effect did the drugs used on adult worms have on adult worms?",
                    "answer": "no effect"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How effective is the first treatment for adult worms?",
                    "score": 0.9295,
                    "answers": "on 02/04/2014|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What drugs are used to treat adult worms?",
                    "score": 0.9211,
                    "answers": "used|acl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the effects of early treatment on adult worms?",
                    "score": 0.882,
                    "answers": "that|mark\tEarly|amod\tEarly treatment|nsubj\tcan|aux\tvery|advmod\tvery effective|acomp\t,|punct\tbut|cc\tthe|det\tno|det\ton adult worms|prep\tadult|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the names of the drugs used on adult worms?",
                    "score": 0.8468,
                    "answers": "the drugs used|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between the use of drugs and adult worms?",
                    "score": 0.8094,
                    "answers": "adult worms|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "How to defeat mosquitoes?For experts, the key to reducing the high number of mosquitoes vectors is to understand how insects behave.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the key to reducing the high number of mosquitoes vectors?",
                    "answer": "to understand how insects behave"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How to defeat mosquitoes?",
                    "score": 0.9142,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 02/04/2014 that How to defeat mosquitoes?For experts|ROOT\tthat How to defeat|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the key to reducing mosquitoes?",
                    "score": 0.8811,
                    "answers": "on 02/04/2014|prep\tHow|advmod\texperts|dobj\tthe key to reducing the high number of mosquitoes vectors|nsubj\tmosquitoes vectors|pobj\t, the key to reducing the high number of mosquitoes vectors is to understand how insects behave|ROOT\tto understand how insects behave|xcomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the best way to combat mosquitoes?",
                    "score": 0.8769,
                    "answers": "high|amod\tmosquitoes|compound\tinsects|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "In addition to insecticides, other methods to control the number of mosquitoes can be odor traps, create genetically modified infertile mosquitoes and even use predatory crustaceans to eat larvae.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What predatory animal is used to eat larvae of mosquitoes?",
                    "answer": "crustaceans"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How do predatory crustaceans eat larvae?",
                    "score": 0.9215,
                    "answers": "even use predatory crustaceans to eat larvae|conj\tpredatory crustaceans|dobj\tto eat larvae|xcomp\tlarvae|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What methods can be used to control mosquitoes?",
                    "score": 0.9099,
                    "answers": "genetically|advmod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the methods used to control the number of mosquitoes?",
                    "score": 0.8479,
                    "answers": "other methods to control the number of mosquitoes|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the use of insecticides to control mosquitoes?",
                    "score": 0.8461,
                    "answers": "insecticides|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many mosquitoes are there in the US?",
                    "score": 0.8221,
                    "answers": "the number of mosquitoes|dobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Professor Hilary Ranson leads a fight against mosquitoes at Liverpool School of Tropical Medicine, and explains that one way to combat these insects is to exploit the fragile dynamics between mosquitoes, viruses and humans.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who leads a fight against mosquitoes at Liverpool School of Tropical Medicine?",
                    "answer": "Professor Hilary Ranson"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Where did Professor Hilary Ranson lead a fight against mosquitoes?",
                    "score": 0.8775,
                    "answers": "Liverpool|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What does Hilary Ranson do to combat mosquitoes?",
                    "score": 0.8325,
                    "answers": "to combat these insects|relcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the process used to combat mosquitoes?",
                    "score": 0.7535,
                    "answers": "one way to combat these insects|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is Hilary Ranson's stance on mosquitoes?",
                    "score": 0.7382,
                    "answers": "Hilary|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between mosquitoes and humans?",
                    "score": 0.7098,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\twww.bbc.com reported on 02/04/2014 that Professor Hilary Ranson leads a fight against mosquitoes at Liverpool School of Tropical Medicine , and explains that one way to combat these insects is to exploit the fragile dynamics between mosquitoes , viruses and humans|ROOT\ton 02/04/2014|prep\tthat|mark\tProfessor|compound\tthat Professor Hilary Ranson leads a fight against mosquitoes at Liverpool School of Tropical Medicine , and explains that one way to combat these insects is to exploit the fragile dynamics between mosquitoes , viruses and humans|ccomp\ta|det\tagainst mosquitoes|prep\tmosquitoes|pobj\tTropical|compound\t,|punct\tand|cc\texplains that one way to combat these insects is to exploit the fragile dynamics between mosquitoes , viruses and humans|conj\tthat|mark\tto|aux\tthese|det\tthese insects|dobj\tthat one way to combat these insects is to exploit the fragile dynamics between mosquitoes , viruses and humans|ccomp\tto|aux\tto exploit the fragile dynamics between mosquitoes , viruses and humans|xcomp\tthe|det\tfragile|amod\tthe fragile dynamics between mosquitoes , viruses and humans|dobj\tbetween mosquitoes , viruses and humans|prep\tmosquitoes , viruses and humans|pobj\t,|punct\tviruses and humans|conj\tand|cc\thumans|conj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "'When the insect stings an infected person, the parasite needs a few *NOMBER* days to develop in your body.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "How long does it take for the parasite to develop in your body?",
                    "answer": "a few *NOMBER* days"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How long do parasites need to develop in their body?",
                    "score": 0.8451,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\ton 02/04/2014|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How long does it take to develop a parasite?",
                    "score": 0.8393,
                    "answers": "the parasite|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The mosquito only has a life of three weeks, so you need to take the pathogen early in your life so you can pass it by.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When did www.bbc.com report that the mosquito only has a life of three weeks?",
                    "answer": "02/04/2014"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the life expectancy of a mosquito?",
                    "score": 0.8564,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\tthat|mark\tThe|det\tThe mosquito|nsubj\tonly|advmod\tThe mosquito only has a life of three weeks|ccomp\ta|det\ta life of three weeks|dobj\tof three weeks|prep\tthree|nummod\t,|punct\tso|mark\tyou|nsubj\tthat The mosquito only has a life of three weeks , so you need to take the pathogen early in your life so you can pass it by|ccomp\tthe|det\tyour life|pobj\tso|mark\tyou|nsubj\tcan|aux\tit|dobj\tby|prt"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How long do you need to take the pathogen early in your life?",
                    "score": 0.853,
                    "answers": "to|aux\tto take the pathogen early in your life so you can pass it by|xcomp\tearly in your life|advmod\tyour|poss"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is a pathogen?",
                    "score": 0.8027,
                    "answers": "the pathogen|dobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "So anything that reduces the daily survival rate will be effective.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did bbc.com say would be effective?",
                    "answer": "anything that reduces the daily survival rate"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What will be done to reduce the daily survival rate?",
                    "score": 0.8842,
                    "answers": "that So anything that reduces the daily survival rate will be effective|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the mortality rate of humans per year?",
                    "score": 0.8823,
                    "answers": "survival|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the average death rate per year?",
                    "score": 0.8455,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 02/04/2014 that So anything that reduces the daily survival rate will be effective|ROOT"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "For its part, Philip McCall's goal is to determine the best way to eradicate mosquitoes with insecticides.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What is Philip McCall's goal?",
                    "answer": "to determine the best way to eradicate mosquitoes with insecticides"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What does Philip McCall want to do with mosquitoes?",
                    "score": 0.8921,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 02/04/2014 that For its part , Philip McCall 's goal is to determine the best way to eradicate mosquitoes with insecticides|ROOT\ton 02/04/2014|prep\tthat|mark\tFor its part|prep\tits|poss\tits part|pobj\t,|punct\tPhilip McCall 's|poss\tthat For its part , Philip McCall 's goal is to determine the best way to eradicate mosquitoes with insecticides|ccomp\tto|aux\tto determine the best way to eradicate mosquitoes with insecticides|xcomp\tthe|det\tto|aux\tto eradicate mosquitoes with insecticides|relcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the best ways to eradicate mosquitoes with insecticides?",
                    "score": 0.8809,
                    "answers": "insecticides|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is Philip McCall's goal with mosquitoes?",
                    "score": 0.8523,
                    "answers": "Philip McCall 's goal|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who is Philip McCall?",
                    "score": 0.7765,
                    "answers": "Philip|compound"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Outdoor nebulization - going everywhere creating a fine insecticide mist - is a very visible method of control, but is often ineffective.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What is a very visible method of insecticide control?",
                    "answer": "Outdoor nebulization"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How is Outdoor nebulization able to control insects?",
                    "score": 0.9071,
                    "answers": "fine|amod\tvery visible|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How effective is Outdoor nebulization?",
                    "score": 0.8875,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\twww.bbc.com reported on 02/04/2014 that Outdoor nebulization - going everywhere creating a fine insecticide mist - is a very visible method of control , but is often ineffective|ROOT\ton 02/04/2014|prep\tthat|mark\t-|punct\teverywhere|advmod\ta|det\t-|punct\tthat Outdoor nebulization - going everywhere creating a fine insecticide mist - is a very visible method of control , but is often ineffective|ccomp\ta|det\tvery|advmod\ta very visible method of control|attr\tof control|prep\tcontrol|pobj\t,|punct\tbut|cc\tis often ineffective|conj\toften|advmod\tineffective|acomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is Outdoor nebulization?",
                    "score": 0.7548,
                    "answers": "Outdoor|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the process used to create an insecticide mist?",
                    "score": 0.7484,
                    "answers": "a fine insecticide mist|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is an insecticide?",
                    "score": 0.7447,
                    "answers": "insecticide|compound"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The spraying behind closed doors, where the insecticide is sprayed inside the walls of the inhabitants to repell or kill mosquitoes, is much more effective, as it attacks them where they like to be.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Where is the insecticide sprayed?",
                    "answer": "inside the walls"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How effective is spraying behind closed doors for mosquitoes?",
                    "score": 0.8983,
                    "answers": "the|det\tthe insecticide|nsubjpass\tthe|det\tthe|det\tmosquitoes|dobj\tthem|dobj\tthey|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the purpose of spraying behind closed doors?",
                    "score": 0.6736,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\tbehind closed doors , where the insecticide is sprayed inside the walls of the inhabitants to repell or kill mosquitoes|prep\tclosed doors , where the insecticide is sprayed inside the walls of the inhabitants to repell or kill mosquitoes|pobj\twhere the insecticide is sprayed inside the walls of the inhabitants to repell or kill mosquitoes|relcl\tinside the walls of the inhabitants|prep\tthe walls of the inhabitants|pobj\tof the inhabitants|prep\tthe inhabitants|pobj\tto repell or kill mosquitoes|advcl\tkill mosquitoes|conj\tthey like where to be|advcl\twhere to be|xcomp"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "'We are working with optical engineers to use sophisticated cameras to track each mosquito, to observe how they move in a three-dimensional space, where their favorite resting sites are ', adds McCall.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the purpose of using cameras to track mosquitoes?",
                    "answer": "to observe how they move in a three-dimensional space, where their favorite resting sites are"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What type of cameras are being used to track each mosquito?",
                    "score": 0.7768,
                    "answers": "sophisticated|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the favorite resting sites for mosquitoes?",
                    "score": 0.734,
                    "answers": "to use sophisticated cameras to track each mosquito , to observe how they move in a three - dimensional space , where their favorite resting sites are|xcomp\tto observe how they move in a three - dimensional space , where their favorite resting sites are|dep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the purpose of using sophisticated cameras to track a mosquito?",
                    "score": 0.7308,
                    "answers": "to track each mosquito|xcomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who are the optical engineers that track each mosquito?",
                    "score": 0.7085,
                    "answers": "optical engineers|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are McCall's favorite resting sites?",
                    "score": 0.6216,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\ton 02/04/2014|prep\tthat|mark\t'|punct\tWe|nsubj\tare|aux\tto|aux\tto|aux\teach|det\t,|punct\tto|aux\tthey|nsubj\ta|det\tthree|advmod\t-|punct\t,|punct\twhere|advmod\ttheir|poss\tfavorite|amod\tresting|amod\ttheir favorite resting sites|nsubj\twhere their favorite resting sites are|relcl\t'|punct\t,|punct"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "So thinking like a mosquito could help scientists control them.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What could help scientists control mosquitoes?",
                    "answer": "thinking like a mosquito"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How can scientists control mosquitoes?",
                    "score": 0.9401,
                    "answers": "like a mosquito|prep\tscientists control them|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did scientists think about mosquito control?",
                    "score": 0.9254,
                    "answers": "that So thinking like a mosquito could help scientists control them|ccomp\tscientists|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the process used to control mosquitoes?",
                    "score": 0.8903,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 02/04/2014 that So thinking like a mosquito could help scientists control them|ROOT\tcould|aux"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the purpose of thinking like a mosquito?",
                    "score": 0.8653,
                    "answers": "thinking like a mosquito|csubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the names of the mosquito that scientists can control?",
                    "score": 0.8627,
                    "answers": "a|det\ta mosquito|pobj"
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}